Neugass, Fritz; Papers ger007
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Fritz Neugass Papers
1913-1979
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
ger007
60 cubic ft.
The collection documents the professional life of photographer and journalist Fritz Neugass. The Neugass Papers include published writings, typescripts, clippings, research materials, photographs by Neugass, photographs by others, correspondence, and auction catalogs.
Biographical Sketch
Fritz W. Neugass (pseudonyms François Neuville and Friedrich Brenatano) was born on the 28th of March 1899 in Mannheim, Baden, Germany to a Protestant-Jewish family. In 1917, he finished school in Mannheim with an end examination (an "Arbitur"), which granted him permission to study at a university. During this time, Neugass was briefly a member of the Wandervogel movement. The following year, Neugass volunteered to serve in the Army. His military career was quickly ended when he was buried in rubble after an engagement with the enemy. Neugass spent the rest of the war in an army hospital, and then as a censor for the post office.
From 1919 to 1924, Neugass was a student of Art and Archeology in Heidelberg (1919-1920), Munich (1920), Berlin (1920-1921), and Bonn (1922-1923). He received his Ph.D. in Heidelberg in 1924. Neugass' dissertation discussed Gothic pews, and was printed in Strassburg within a series of art historical studies. Shortly thereafter, Neugass found employment as a lab assistant at the German Archeological Institute in Rome, and at the German Institute for history in Florence. During this time, he participated in many archeological excavations in Italy.
Neugass spent the years 1926 to 1939 as a resident of Paris, where he worked as an art correspondent for German and Swiss newspapers and art magazines, such as Berliner Tageblatt, Vossische Zeitung, Weltkunst, and others. After 1933, his work was no longer accepted in Germany. This led Neugass to work for various American, British, and French periodicals. He often used the pseudonyms François Neuville and Friedrich Brenatano at this time. Much of Neugass' time was spent in the nations around the Mediterranean, where he took a large number of photographs.
In 1939, French authorities labeled Neugass an "enemy alien" and interned him in Antibes and in Les Milles. Neugass later wrote a novel about his experiences in the French detention camps. In 1940, he arrived in Free France (Cannes), and applied unsuccessfully for an American visa through the Emergency Rescue Commission of Varian Fry. Nevertheless, Neugass managed to emigrate to the United states via Casablanca in December 1941 just before a Vichy court found Neugass guilty of "enemy propaganda".
Shortly after his arrival in the U.S., Neugass worked as a swimming instructor and as a nurse. He made various unsuccessful applications to join the U.S. Army or to work in the war industry. While taking night-classes to learn blueprint drawing, Neugass performed volunteer work for the Red Cross of New York City. Not long before the end of the War, Neugass joined the New York City Patrol Corps. He also worked with the Volunteer Service Photographers (who aided paraplegic G.I.'s with photography).
In 1944, Neugass married Lotte Labus, who had earned her own Ph.D in Berlin. Labus and Neugass had met in the U.S. When the War ended, Neugass became a free-lance photographer. He published photos and articles in American and European photo magazines, such as Aufbau, New Yorker, New Yorker Staats- Zeitung und Herold, and Art News. He became a member of the American Society of Magazine Photographers, and had an exhibition of his work at the Village Camera Club. In 1954, the American Museum of Natural History held an exhibit of several dozen photographs that Neugass had taken in Mexico the previous year.
After 1947, Neugass re-established contact with various German newspapers and magazines, and became a correspondent on the subjects of art, architecture, the art market, and photography. He later became a permanent contributor to the Frankfurter Allgemeine Zeitung, Handelsblatt, and other European art and photography magazines. Neugass often wrote for the American art magazine Art Voices.
In January 1979, Neugass was forced to turn down an offer to act as the American editor for a new German magazine (Art) due to poor health. He passed away in June. A memorial exhibit of Neugass' work was held on the 15th of October 1979 at the Goethe House of New York City.
Exhibits of photography by Fritz Neugass:
1954: American Museum of Natural History exhibit of photographs that were taken by Fritz Neugass in Mexico in 1953.
1959 (July-August): Chautauqua Art Association Gallery exhibit of photographs by Fritz Neugass.
(ca. 1959): Village Camera Club exhibit of photographs that were taken by Fritz Neugass in New York City and in Europe.
1979 (October 15): Goethe House of New York City memorial exhibit of photographs by Fritz Neugass.
Sources
Roder, Werner. International Biographical Dictionary of Central European Émigrés (New York: Gale Research Company, 1980): 854.
Telephone interview with Mrs. Lotte Neugass, 8 June 1990.
Scope and Contents
Fritz Neugass was a professional photographer and journalist as early as 1926, when he first moved to Paris. He was active almost until the day of his death in 1979. The earliest photographs in the collection (not including his personal family pictures) date from the 1930s (few of these images have specific dates written on them.) The dates for the entire collection of papers and photographs range from 1913 to 1979. There are many gaps in time for this collection, which is to be expected in a set of personal papers.
The basic arrangement of the Neugass Papers was completed by Lotte Neugass prior to their deposit at the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections. The collection was divided into two main sections. Section one contains mostly typewritten notes (in German and in English), photographs, books, and clippings from periodicals. This material relates to various museum art exhibits and art auctions that took place from the early 1950s to the 1970s. Other papers discuss the work of well-known artists and styles of art, as well as contemporary news events. Much, if not most, of the above material apparently served as sources for articles that were written by Neugass. The second section, almost exclusively photographs, includes personal family pictures, views in and around New York City, images from his travels overseas (and his days as a photojournalist in the 1930s), studies of patterns and faces, prints by other photographers, and mounted images for his exhibits of images from New York City and Mexico. As few of these prints have any dates, they have been organized largely by subject. There are approximately 4500 original photographs by Neugass in the collection.
Arrangement of the Collection
The Neugass Papers have been divided into sixteen series. The first nine series (corresponding to section one of the original Lotte Neugass arrangement) consist of typewritten texts by Neugass in English and German, photographs (not taken by Neugass) used by Neugass to accompany his articles, and clippings used by Neugass in his writing. The series are arranged by subject: Series 1: Art and Artists; Series 2: Museums & Private Collections; Series 3: Art market, art auctions; Series 4: Architecture & Architects; Series 5: Furniture and Design; Series 6: Theater and Film; Series 7: Photography and Photographers; Series 8: General journalistic articles; and Series 9: Articles with text and photos by Neugass. The remaining series include: Series 10: Published writings by Neugass, 1942-1979; Series 11: Early writings (pre-US) of Fritz Neugass, 1930s-1940; Series 12: Documents and biographical materials, 1899-1979; Series 13: Correspondence, 1941-1979; Series 14: Photographs by Fritz Neugass, 1930s-1970s; Series 15: Photographs by other artists; Series 16: Sotheby Parke-Bernet auction catalogs, 1931-1979.
Acquisition Information
All items in the collection were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, by Lotte Labus Neugass on June 20, 1983.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Art; Architecture; Art criticism.; Photographic criticism.; Photography--Exhibitions.; Exiles' writings, German.; New York (N.Y.)--Photographs; Cape Cod (Mass.)--Photographs; Provincetown (Mass.)--Photographs; Mexico--Photographs; France--Photographs; Italy--Photographs; Greece--Photographs; Turkey--Photographs; Autobiographies; Manuscripts; Photographs; Correspondence; Lithographs; Painting; Neugass, Fritz, 1899-1979.; Village Camera Club.; American Museum of Natural History.; Westdeutscher Rundfunk.
- Art and Artists, 1950s-1979; 1; 260 file folders
  Scope and Contents
  This series consists of typescripts by Neugass, photographs and clippings on art genres and individual artists.
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - Ägypt: Egypt. Egyptian Sculpture of the Late Period, Exhibit Brooklyn Museum, 1961 (Box 1 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 1)
    Typescript, photographs (7).
  - Ägyptische Kunst: Egyptian Art: El Amarna, Echnaton, Nofretete. Exhibit Brooklyn Museum, 1973 (Box 1 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 2)
    Typescripts (2), photographs (2), publicity, clippings.
  - Ägyptische Kunst: Egyptian Art: Temple of Dendur: Exhibit Metropolitan Museum 1978, Nubian Art, Exhibit in Brooklyn Museum (Box 1 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 3)
    Typescript, photographs (30), publicity, clippings.
  - African Art. Ancient cities of Benin, Ifé, Undated (Box 1 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 4)
    Typescripts (4), notes, photographs (27), publicity, clippings.
    See also Box 25, Folder 1.
  - Afro-Amerikanische Kunst: Afro-American Art, Undated (Box 1 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 5)
    Typescript, photographs (5), publicity, clippings.
    See also Box 25, Folder 2.
  - Akt-Malerei. The Nude in Painting, Undated (Box 1 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 6)
    Typescripts (3) in English and in German, photographs (2).
  - Albright, Ivan, Undated (Box 1 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 7)
    Typescript, photographs (11), clippings.
  - Alechinsky, Pierre. Prize and Exhibition at Carnegie Institute, Pittsburgh, 1977 (Box 1 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 8)
    Typescript, photographs (14), clippings.
  - Alma-Tadema, Sir Lawrence, Undated (Box 1 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 9)
    Typescripts (2), photographs (5), clippings.
  - American Census of Manuscripts. Book review of William H. Bond's book, 1962; typescript (Box 1 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 10)
  - Amerika aus europaischer Sicht: "The European vision of America". 200-year anniversary of the U.S. exhibit, 1976 (Box 1 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 11)
    Typescript, photographs (6), publicity, catalog, clippings.
  - Amerikanische Malerei. American Painting of the 20th Century, Undated (Box 1 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 12)
    Typescripts (5), photographs (56), clippings.
  - Amerikanische Malerei. American Painting, 200 years of, Undated (Box 1 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 13)
    Typescripts (4), photographs (141), clippings.
  - Amerikanische Volksmalerei. American Folk Art, Undated (Box 1 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 14)
    See also under Moses, Grandma. Typescript, photographs (13), clippings.
  - Amsterdam - Paris - Dusseldorf. Exhibit at Guggenheim Museum, 1972 (Box 1 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 15)
    With catalog. Typescript, photographs (3).
  - Der Antike / Antiquity, Undated (Box 1 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 16)
    Typescript, photographs (5).
  - Aretino, Pietro. 400th anniversary of his death, 1956 (Box 1 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 17)
    Typescripts (5), photographs (34), clipping.
  - Armory Show, New York, 50th Anniversary, 1963 (Box 1 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 18)
    Typescript, photographs (7), clippings.
  - Aronson, David. Catalog, Undated (Box 1 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 19)
  - Arp, Jean (Hans). Exhibit at the re-opening of the Museum of Modern Art, 1953 (Box 1 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 20)
    With original photos by Fritz Neugass. Notes, photographs (21), clippings.
  - Artists' Self Portraits. Metropolitan Museum's exhibit "Portrait of the Artist", 1972 (Box 1 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 21)
    No text by Fritz Neugass. Catalog, photographs (9), photocopies, publicity.
  - Art Establishment and Art Experts in America, Undated (Box 1 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 22)
    Clippings, no text by Fritz Neugass.
  - Art and Government, Foundations, Undated (Box 1 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 23)
    Clippings, no Fritz Neugass text.
  - Baerwind, Rudi. Handwritten letter to Fritz Neugass, no Neugass text, catalogs, Undated (Box 1 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 24)
  - Balthus. Exhibit in Pierre Matisse Gallery, 1978 (Box 1 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 25)
    Typescript, photographs (4), publicity, clippings.
  - Barlach, Ernst. Book review of Alfred Werner's book, 1966 (Box 1 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 26)
    Typescript, clippings.
  - Bearden, Romare, Undated (Box 1 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 27)
    Typescript, photographs (18), illustrated catalogues.
  - Beckmann, Max. Retrospective in USA, 1964 (Box 1 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 28)
    Typescripts (2), photographs (6), clippings.
  - Belgische Kunst: Belgian Art. No text by Neugass, Undated (Box 1 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 29)
    Publicity, photographs (9), catalog.
  - Berenson, Bernard, Undated (Box 1 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 30)
    Typescript, notes, photograph (by Neugass), clippings.
  - Berry, Duc de. Book of Hours, Undated (Box 1 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 31)
    Typescripts (5), photographs (20), clippings, publicity.
  - Berthold, Joachim, Undated (Box 2 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 1)
    Typescripts (2), photographs (48), clippings, publicity materials, correspondence. Original lithograph, signed (stored in vault).
  - Berthold, Joachim. Catalogues and prospectuses, Undated (Box 2 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 1a)
  - Beuys, Joseph, Undated; typescript, clippings (Box 2 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 2)
  - Biblical Manuscripts: Dead Sea Scrolls, Bibles, Undated (Box 2 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 3)
    Typescripts (3), photographs (4), clippings.
  - Binder, Joseph, Undated (Box 2 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 4)
    Typescript, catalog, publicity.
  - Blake William. Exhibit at National Gallery, 1957 (Box 2 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 5)
    No text by Neugass. Photographs (3), publicity, clippings.
  - Bonnard, Pierre, Undated (Box 2 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 6)
    Typescript, photographs (4), clippings.
  - Braque, Georges, Undated (Box 2 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 7)
    Typescripts (3), photographs (16), clippings.
  - Brancusi, Constantin. Exhibit at Guggenheim Museum, no text by Neugass, Undated (Box 2 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 8)
    Photographs (11), publicity, clippings.
  - Calder, Alexander, Undated (Box 2 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 9)
    Typescripts (4), photographs (37), publicity, clippings.
  - Caravaggio, Michelangelo Merisi de. "Caravaggio and His Followers", exhibit Cleveland Museum 1971, no text by Neugass, Undated (Box 2 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 10)
    Photographs (7), publicity.
  - Cassatt, Mary, Undated (Box 2 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 11)
    Typescript, photographs (10), publicity, clippings.
  - Catlin, Georg, Undated (Box 2 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 12)
    Typescript, photographs (44), clippings.
  - Cellini, Benvenuto. Discovery of a marble bust, 1965 (Box 2 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 13)
    Typescript, photographs (3), clippings.
  - Cézanne, Paul, Undated (Box 2 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 14)
    Typescripts (2), photographs (16), publicity, clippings.
  - Cézanne, Paul. Late work, exhibit at the Museum of Modern Art, 1977 (Box 2 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 15)
    Typescripts (2), photographs (19), publicity, clippings.
  - Chagall, Marc, Undated (Box 2 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 16)
    Typescripts (2), clippings.
  - China: Odyssey of Chinese art works, Undated (Box 2 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 17)
    Typescript, photographs (27), publicity, clippings.
  - Chinese Fresco in Kansas City, 1953 (Box 2 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 18)
    Typescript, photographs (8), clipping.
  - Chinesische Kunst unter den Mongolen. Exhibit "Chinese Art Under the Mongols", Cleveland Museum 1960, no text by Neugass, Undated (Box 2 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 19)
    Photographs (11), publicity.
  - Churchill, Winston, as a painter, Undated (Box 2 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 20)
  - Corinth, Lovis, Undated (Box 2 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 21)
    Typescript, letter from Thomas Corinth, photographs (2), publicity, clippings.
  - Cornell, Joseph. Notes, no Fritz Neugass article, Undated (Box 2 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 22)
    Photographs (11), clippings.
  - Corot, Jean-Baptiste-Camille. Catalog by Wildenstein, 1969 (Box 2 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 23)
    See also Box 25, Folder 3.
    No text by Neugass. Photographs (12), clippings.
  - Cubism. No text by Fritz Neugass, Undated (Box 2 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 24)
    Photographs (17), publicity, clippings.
  - Dali, Salvador, Undated (Box 2 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 25)
    Typescripts (4), photographs (8), publicity, clippings.
  - Daumier, Honoré, Undated (Box 2 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 26)
    Typescript, photographs (14), publicity, clippings.
  - Davis, Stuart. Exhibit Brooklyn Museum, 1978 (Box 2 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 27)
    No text by Fritz Neugass. Photographs (2), publicity, clippings.
  - Degas, Edgar, Undated (Box 2 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 28)
    Typescripts (2), photographs (62), publicity, clippings.
  - Deutsche Kunst: German Art of the 19th century in USA, Undated (Box 2 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 29)
    Typescripts (5), photographs (27), clippings.
  - Deutsche Kunst: German Art of the 20th century in USA, Undated (Box 2 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 30)
    Numerous articles, including short essays on Liebermann, Eva Hesse, with original photos by Fritz Neugass.
    Typescripts (16), photographs (48), clippings.
  - Dubuffet, Jean. No text by Fritz Neugass, Undated (Box 3 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 1)
    Photographs (15), publicity, clippings.
  - Dürer, Albrecht, Undated (Box 3 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 2)
    Typescripts (8), publicity, clippings.
  - Dürer, Albrecht, Undated (Box 3 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 3)
    Photographs (67).
  - Early Christian Art. "Age of Spirituality" exhibit in Metropolitan Museum, 1978 (Box 3 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 4)
    Catalog, numerous notes and inscriptions of photos, no finished text by Fritz Neugass. Photographs (21), publicity, clippings.
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D., as a painter, Undated (Box 3 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 5)
    Typescripts (2), photographs (9), clippings.
  - English Painting 1800-1950. Museum of Modern Art and other exhibits, Undated (Box 3 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 6)
    Typescript, photographs (6), publicity, clippings.
  - Ensor, James. Guggenheim Museum exhibit, notes by Fritz Neugass but no finished text, Undated (Box 3 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 7)
    Photographs (2), publicity, clippings.
  - Ernst, Jimmy, Undated (Box 3 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 8)
    Typescripts, photographs (15), clippings.
  - Ernst, Max, including original photos by Fritz Neugass, Undated (Box 3 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 9)
    Typescripts (4), photographs (20), clippings.
    See also Box 25, Folder 4.
  - Eskimo Art: Volkskunst, Undated (Box 3 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 10)
    Typescript, photograph (1), clippings.
  - Fakes. Articles by Fritz Neugass, Undated (Box 3 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 11)
    Typescripts (17), notes.
  - Fakes: Material, Undated (Box 3 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 12)
    Including Exhibit in Amsterdam, 1968, and in Minneapolis, 1973. Photographs (36).
  - Fakes: clippings, Undated (Box 3 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 13)
  - Fakes: Elmyr de Hory affair, Clifford Irving's Book Fake, with printed articles by Fritz Neugass, Undated (Box 3 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 14)
  - Fauvismus: Fauvism. Exhibit in Museum of Modern Art, 1976 (Box 3 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 15)
    Typescript, notes, photographs (5), publicity, clippings.
  - Feininger, Andreas. Reviews of books and exhibits, with original photos by Feininger, Undated (Box 3 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 16)
    Typescripts (5), photographs (4), publicity, clippings.
    See also Box 25, Folder 5.
  - Figurliche Malerei: Paintings of the human figure, Undated (Box 3 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 17)
    Typescripts (3), photographs (8), publicity, clippings.
  - Frauen als Künstler: Women as Artists. Exhibit Brooklyn Museum, 1977 (Box 3 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 18)
    Typescript, notes, correspondence, photographs (12), publicity, clippings.
  - French Painting, 17th century. Exhibit "Splendid Century" in the Metropolitan Museum, 1961 (Box 3 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 19)
    No text by Fritz Neugass. Photographs (7), publicity, clippings.
  - French Painting 1774-1830. Exhibit "Age of Revolution" in Metropolitan Museum, 1975 (Box 3 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 20)
  - French Painting 1900-1967. Traveling Exhibit in USA, 1968 (Box 3 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 21)
    With illustrated catalog. Typescript, photographs (11), clippings.
  - French Painting. Graphic art exhibit "Three Centuries of French Satire", 1964 (Box 3 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 22)
    With illustrated catalog, no text by Fritz Neugass.
  - Futurismus: Futurism, Exhibit at the Museum of Modern Art, 1961 (Box 3 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 23)
    Typescript, photographs (16), clippings.
  - Gauguin, Paul, Undated (Box 3 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 24)
    Typescripts (2), photographs (12), publicity, clippings.
  - German contemporary art. Exhibit "Berlin Now" in New York, 1977 (Box 3 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 25)
    With illustrated catalog. Typescripts (2), photographs (5), publicity, clippings.
  - Giacometti, Alberto, Undated (Box 3 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 26)
    Includes exhibit at the Guggenheim Museum, "Giacometti and three Swiss Painters", 1974. Typescripts (2), photographs (22), publicity, clippings.
  - Gold through the millennia. Exhibit at Metropolitan Museum, 1973 (Box 3 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 27)
    Typescripts (3), photographs (5), publicity, clippings.
  - Goya, Francisco, including doubtful Wellington Portrait, also Loan-exhibit from the Prado at the Mertop Museum, 1976 (Box 3 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 28)
    Typescripts (2), photographs (36), publicity, clippings.
  - Graphic Art. Reviews of books on graphic art, Undated (Box 3 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 29)
    Typescripts (2), correspondence, photographs (15), clippings.
  - El Greco (Dominicos Theotocopoulos), Undated (Box 4 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 1)
    Typescript, photographs (3).
  - Grünewald, Matthias, including purchase of a Grunewald fake by the Cleveland Museum, Undated (Box 4 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 2)
    Typescript, correspondence, photograph (1), clippings.
  - Halkin, Theodore, Undated (Box 4 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 3)
    Typescript, photograph, clippings.
  - Hamburg Views. Exhibit at Knoedler's, 1967 (Box 4 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 4)
    With illustrated catalog, typescript.
  - Hanson, Duane. Exhibit in Whitney Museum 1978, no text by Fritz Neugass, Undated (Box 4 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 5)
    Photographs (5), publicity, clippings.
  - Hodler, Ferdinand. Exhibit at Guggenheim Museum, 1973 (Box 4 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 6)
    Typescript, photographs (6), clippings.
  - Hofmann, Hans, including original photos by Fritz Neugass, Undated (Box 4 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 7)
    Typescripts (3), photographs (7), publicity, clippings.
  - Houdon, Jean Antoine, Undated (Box 4 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 8)
    Typescripts (2), photographs (18), clippings.